我们在本次讲座中涵盖了很多领域，让我们回顾一些更重要的观点。
We've covered a lot of territory in this lecture, let's recap some of the more important points.
执行器是引起运动的装置-可以引起线性或旋转运动，以及它们
Actuators are devices that cause motion — that can cause linear or rotary motion, and they
可以产生速度或力量。它们可以基于许多不同的物理
can generate either a speed or a force. They can be based on a number of different physical
原则;它们可以是液压，气动或电动。
principles; they can be hydraulic, pneumatic, or electric.
在大多数机器人中，电动是最常用的致动器类型。大多数机器人
In most robots, electric is the most common type of actuator that's used. Most robots
由电动机驱动采用减速齿轮箱。电动机能够旋转
driven by electric motors employ a reduction gear box. Electric motors are capable of spinning
非常快，但他们往往具有相对较低的扭矩。减速齿轮箱放大
very very quickly, but they tend to have relatively low torque. A reduction gearbox amplifies
以电机速度为代价的电机转矩。我们引入了“S”作为运营商
the motor's torque at the expense of the motor's speed. We introduced "S" as an operator to
将微分方程转换为代数方程，即一个特征方程
convert a differential equation into an algebraic equation, a characteristic equation, which
代表了潜在的机械或电气系统的动态。特征的根源
represents the dynamics of an underlying mechanical or electrical system. The roots of the characteristic
方程式被称为系统的极点。他们描述了反应
equation are referred to as the poles of the system. And they describe the response of
系统作为时间的函数。
the system as a function of time.
对于具有多个极点的系统，总体响应是响应的超级位置，
For a system with multiple poles, the overall response is the super position of the response,
由于每个极点。我们介绍了传递函数的概念。
due to each of the individual poles. We introduced the notion of a transfer function.
在拉普拉斯域中，它是电阻输出与其输入的比率。
And in the laplace domain it is the ratio of resistance output to it's input.
大多数机械系统包含摩擦力有两种重要的摩擦类型：
Most mechanical systems incorporate friction. There are two important classes of friction:
线性摩擦和非线性摩擦有时被称为库仑摩擦。
linear friction, and non-linear friction which is sometimes referred to as coulomb friction.
一个现实的摩擦模型看起来像这样。它有正面和负面
A realistic friction model looks something like this. It has a positive and negative
库仑摩擦值和线性斜率“B”。
coulomb friction value and a linear slope "B".
摩擦力总是与运动方向相反。和摩擦特性一样
The friction force always opposes the direction of motion. And a friction characteristic like
对于零速度的情况，这没有定义。对于电流控制的电动机，
this is not defined for the case of zero velocity. For a current controlled electrical motor,
我们可以用电机常数，它的惯性和它来写出它的传递函数
we can write its transfer function in terms of the motor constant, it's inertia, and it's
摩擦。
friction.
电动机控制系统需要一种测量电动机轴角度的装置。而且最多
A motor control system needs a means of measuring the angle of the motor shaft. And the most
常见的方法是使用增量编码器，两个光束照射通过
common way this is done is with an incremental encoder with two light beams shine through
安装在电机轴上的圆盘槽。
slots in a disk attached to the motor shaft.
我们可以分析这些信号，以确定电机的速度和方向
We can analyze these signals to determine the velocity of the motor and the direction
轮换。通过计算脉冲并知道方向，我们可以确定
of rotation. And by counting the pulses and knowing the direction, we can determine the
电机轴的角度。我们将许多这些组件组合在一起以创建机器人
angle of the motor shaft. We bring a number of these components together to create a robot
联合控制员。
joint controller.
联合控制器本身通常是在嵌入式控制器中运行的算法。
The joint controller itself is typically an algorithm running in an embedded controller.
电动机驱动器通常是包括四个电子开关的H桥电路。开关
The motor drive is typically an H-bridge circuit comprising four electronic switches. The switches
可以很快打开和关闭，这使我们不仅可以控制方向
can be turned on and off very quickly which allows us to control not only the direction
电流流过电动机，但是电动机经历的平均电压。
the current flows through the motor, but the average voltage that the motor experiences.
电机的输出通过机械传动装置通过机械传动装置连接，
The output of the motor is connected through the robot joint by a mechanical transmission,
减速齿轮箱，用于放大电动机的扭矩。
a reduction gearbox which amplifies the torque of the motor.
使用位置传感器测量电机的位置。通常，这是一种光学
The position of the motor is measured with a position sensor. Typically, that's an optical
增量编码器。与之相比，该信息反馈给联合控制器
incremental encoder. That information is fed back to the joint controller compared with
理想的位置。并且这两者之间的误差也用于驱动电动机
the desired position. And the error between those two is used to drive the motor either
向前或向后以最小化错误。
forwards or backwards to minimize the error.
我们可以创建这个机器人联合控制系统的动态模型。
We can create a dynamic model of this robot joint control system.
我们有一个代表联合控制器的块和负反馈求和
We have a block which represents the joint controller, and the negative feedback summing
结。电机驱动器的输出是电流，进入我们的执行器模型。
junction. The output of the motor driver is current which goes into our model of the actuator.
该块的输出是电机的位置。我们将传感器建模为增益
The output of that block is the position of the motor. We model the sensor as a gain of
一，它向关节控制器提供负反馈信号。
one, which provides the negative feedback signal to the joint controller.
机器人关节的最大加速度是最大扭矩的函数
The maximum acceleration of a robot joint is a function of the maximum torque that the
电动机可以产生，这是电动机转矩常数和最大值的函数
motor can generate and that's a function of the motor torque constant and the maximum
可以送入电机的电流。它也是惯性的函数
current that can be fed into the motor. And it's also a function of the inertia that the
运动经验。
motor experiences.
惯性有两个组成部分：一个组件是电机自身的电枢惯性
That inertia has got two components: one component is the motor's own armature inertia and that's
一个常数。另一个组成部分是链路的惯性。
a constant. The other component is the inertia of the link.
在真实的机器人中，链路惯性是高度可变的。这是因为在串行链接中
In a real robot, the link inertia is highly variable. And that's because in a serial link
操纵器，每个链接都必须支撑所有后续链接。作为关节角度
manipulator, each link has to hold up all of the subsequent links. As the joint angles
所有这些板外链接都随时间变化，这种电机的惯性也会随之变化。
of all of those out board links varies with time, so will the inertia that this motor experiences.
然而，通常在电动机和连杆之间存在齿轮箱，这就是效果
However, typically there is a gearbox between the motor and the link and that is the effect
通过“G”平方因子减少链路惯性。通常，“G”是一个很大的数字，
of reducing the inertia of the link by a factor of "G" squared. Typically, "G" is a big number,
可能是十，可能是一百;这大大减少了这种可变惯性
could be ten, could be a hundred; and that dramatically reduces this variable inertia
由于链接配置。
due to the link configuration.
多关节机器人通常采用所谓的独立关节控制
Multi-joint robots typically employ what's called independent joint control so there
是每个单独关节的独立机器人关节控制器。通常这些控制器
is a separate robot joint controller for each individual joint. Typically these controllers
有一个共同的电子和软件设计。通常，只有几个参数
have a common electronic and software design. And typically, only a few parameters in the
需要更换联合控制器以适应安装的不同尺寸的电机
joint controller need to be changed to accommodate the different sized motors that are fitted
到机器人的不同关节。
to different joints of the robot.